linuxjournal.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Statement | Linux Journal

## LINUX JOURNAL PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy outlines the privacy practices for Linux Journal, LLC (“We,” “Us,” or “Company”), regarding access to the Company website and online subscriptions (“Services") offered by Company. This document ('Privacy Policy') defines and informs our data subjects of any and all of the instances in which your data and information (collectively, ‘Personal Information') may be saved and how it may be used by Linux Journal, third-parties, and finally the level of protection we use to safeguard your personal information. The processing of personal information herein shall always be in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to Linux Journal. By means of this data protection declaration and privacy policy, we would like to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal information we collect, use and process. Furthermore, data subjects are informed, by means of this data protection declaration, of the rights to which they are entitled.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

  1. Personal Information we Collect
  2. Uses of Personal Information we Collect
  3. Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties
  4. Cookies and other Tracking Technologies
  5. CalOPPA Statement
  6. Maintaining the Security of Your Personal Information
  7. How We Transfer Information Collected Internationally
  8. COPPA Disclosure
  9. Rights of the Data Subject
  10. Data Retention
  11. Legal Basis for Data Processing
  12. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  13. How to Contact Linux Journal

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**From all Users**

  * We retain apache web server logs for improvement of delivery of services
  * We use one or more cookies for improvement of delivery of services

Our third party service providers, as explained further in the "Collection of Information by Third-Parties" section below, may also collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit our web pages, open our emails, use our applications, or otherwise use the Services, including such information as the type of browser and operating system you are using, your IP address, your device identifiers, your Internet or wireless service provider, location-based information, and the content and advertisements you have interacted with, viewed, or accessed. This data may be combined and linked with data from other sources for the purposes of improving delivery of our services to you.

**From our Subscribers**

Via the Services offered by Company, you may, among other activities, vote in one or more polls or express one or more opinions; you can subscribe to one of our services, or sign up to receive periodic newsletters. We collect the information, including any personally identifiable information, that you provide to us in the course of using the Services. The types of information that may be collected through these Services include, but are not limited to: name, postal code, payment information, and e-mail address.

**USES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
Company may use the personal information collected from data subjects under this Privacy Policy in the following ways:

  * If you submit any user-generated content (e.g., a "letter to our editors" or an online review), we may publish your name, screen name and other information you have provided to us,
  * Company may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill requests for our publications, products or services, to respond to inquiries about offerings and to offer other products, programs or services that may be of interest,
  * Company sometimes uses this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests or sweepstakes, when we make changes to subscriber agreements, or to contact you about your account,
  * Company may use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our publications and websites, and to enable us to customize your Internet experience. We also may use this information to analyze site usage, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services,
  * Company will disclose information that is maintained when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. Company also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request,
  * Contractors, other third-parties, and agents working with Linux Journal, LLC that have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing on behalf of Linux Journal, LLC, and
  * Please note that if Linux Journal, LLC is merged, acquired, divested, financed, sold, disposed of or dissolved, including through merger of, consolidation, sale or divestiture of assets, the relevant customer database, including personally identifiable information Company may possess about you, may, in whole or in part, be sold, disposed of, transferred, divested, or otherwise disclosed as part of that transaction or proceeding.

**DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**  
Some of our Services contain links to third party sites and services whose privacy practices may be different than ours. We also allow you to connect with other third party sites and services. You should consult the other third party sites' and services' privacy notices in order to better understand their privacy practices. Company sometimes may offer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, editorial features, or other activities or offerings that are sponsored or co-sponsored by or presented with identified third parties. By virtue of your participation in such activities or offerings, your IP address and the personally identifiable information that you voluntarily submit may be provided to both Linux Journal, LLC and third parties. Linux Journal, LLC has no control over how third parties' may use this information. Company may use third parties to present or serve advertisements, including online behavioral advertisements, that you may see on the Services and to conduct research about the advertisements-or the Services themselves.

**COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**  
"Cookies" may be placed on your computer or device if you are using the Linux Journal website. Cookies are small text files that we place in your computer or device to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personal information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering with one of our Services. Once you choose to provide us with personal information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. A cookie assigns a unique numerical identifier to your Web browser or device, and may enable us to recognize you as the same user who has used our Services, and relate your use of the Services to other information about you, such as your usage information and personal information. Company uses cookies (Drupal Session cookie and Google Analytics cookie) to understand usage of the Services and to improve our content. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience on our Services (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our site, to save your password in password-protected areas, to enable shopping carts).

**CalOPPA STATEMENT**  
The State of California requires us to post specific language related to our privacy policy. By default, Company does not share your private information with any third parties aside from the disclosures already made in this privacy policy. However, if you wish to inquire into how Company does not share our user's private information with third parties for direct marketing purposes, you may contact: [privacy@linuxjournal.com](mailto:privacy@linuxjournal.com).

**MAINTAINING THE SECURITY OF YOUR PRIVATE INFORMATION**  
Your private information is safeguarded by Company. Only some employees are granted access to the servers and information where private information is maintained. Private information is maintained in an encrypted form.

**HOW WE TRANSFER INFORMATION COLLECTED INTERNATIONALLY**  
We collect information globally and primarily store that information in the United States. If We transfer your information from ___m We will request your consent.

**COPPA DISCLOSURE**  
The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was passed to give parents increased control over what information is collected from their children online and how such information is used. The law applies to websites and services directed to, and which knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13. Our online services are not directed to children under the age of 13, nor is information knowingly collected from them. For additional information on COPPA protections, please see the FTC website at: [https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-priva…](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online)

**RIGHTS OF THE DATA SUBJECT**  
Company shall take reasonable steps to accurately record the personal information that you provide to us and any subsequent updates. You are encouraged to review, update, and correct any personal information that we maintain about you, and you may request that we delete personal information about you that is inaccurate, incomplete, or irrelevant for legitimate purposes, or is processed in a manner that violates any applicable legal requirements for the handling of personal information, by contacting us as provided herein. You may request to review, edit, correct, or delete your personal information at any time by contacting our support team. Your right to review, update, correct, and delete your personal information may be limited, subject to the law or your jurisdiction: (i) where the rights or safety of another person or persons would be encroached upon, (ii) if the information or material you request relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between you and us, or providing access to you would prejudice negotiations between us or an investigation of possible unlawful activity, or (iii) if your requests are abusive and/or unreasonably excessive. Your right to review, update, correct and delete your information is subject to our records retention policies and applicable federal and state data retention laws.

**RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
Company shall retain your personal information while you as a data subject maintain an account with us and thereafter for as long as it is necessary for purposes not prohibited by applicable laws. Upon your request, the data controller will either delete your personal information or de-identify it so that it is anonymous and not attributed to your identity. Requests that we delete your personal information can be sent to our customer support team.

**LEGAL BASIS FOR DATA PROCESSING**  
Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing operations for which we obtain consent for a specific processing purpose. If the processing of personal information is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the information subject is party, as is the case, for example, when processing operations are necessary for the supply of goods or to provide any other service, the processing is based on Article 6(1) lit. b GDPR. The same applies to such processing operations which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures, for example in the case of inquiries concerning our products or services. If our company is subject to a legal obligation by which processing of personal information is required, such as for the fulfillment of tax obligations, the processing is based on Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR. In rare cases, the processing of personal information may be necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person. Then the processing would be based on Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR. Finally, processing operations could be based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR. This legal basis is used for processing operations which are not covered by any of the aforementioned legal grounds, if processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our company or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal information. Such processing operations are particularly permissible because they have been specifically mentioned by the European legislator. He considered that a legitimate interest could be assumed if the data subject is a client of the controller (Recital 47 Sentence 2 GDPR).

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
BY USING THIS WEBSITE AND/OR SERVICES, YOU AGREE THAT YOU AS THE DATA SUBJECT CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOU AGREE THAT LINUXJOURNAL MAY MAKE CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AT ANY TIME WITHOUT ANY GIVEN NOTICE AT ITS DISCRETION.

**HOW TO CONTACT US**  
If you have any questions about the Linux Journal, LLC Privacy Policy or the current version of the Privacy Policy please contact us via email, [privacy@linuxjournal.com](mailto:privacy@linuxjournal.com), or by writing to:

Linux Journal, LLC  
Attention: Privacy Policy Administrator  
9597 Jones Rd #331  
Houston, TX 77065  USA
